Guide to the Stephen G. Bickford Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Stephen G. Bickford papers
1980-1999
MS 1977
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.25
(3 boxes)
The Stephen G. Bickford papers consist of correspondence, photographs, newspaper clippings, primarily concerning USAF GLOBE, an organization founded by Bickford to advocate for gay, lesbian, bisexual and transgender non discrimination for civilians in the Air Force.
Bickford, Stephen G.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in three sections: Air Force Gay and Lesbian Or Bisexual Employees (GLOBE) files, Personal files, and Topical files.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Stephen G. Bickford, 2011.
Biographical / Historical
Stephen Gard Bickford was born in Lewiston, Maine, on December 7, 1954, and was educated at the University of Connecticut and the University of Idaho where he studied mathematics and architecture respectively. In 1980, Mr. Bickford accepted a position with the United States Air Force at Wright-Patterson Air Force Base near Dayton, Ohio, where he worked in the design and construction of Air Force facilities, building additions and renovations. In 1993, following President Bill Clinton's pledge to support the rights of gay federal workers, Bickford "came out" and began to advocate for the rights of gay Air Force civilian employees. On March 13, 1997, Bickford established USAF GLOBE (Gay and Lesbian or Bisexual Employees), a nationwide organization to help gay or lesbian civilian employees of the U.S. Air Force. The mission of USAF GLOBE was to educate gay and lesbian employees on their rights against non-job related conduct discrimination and federal guidelines related to sexual orientation.
Mr. Bickford served as the president of USAF GLOBE from 1997 to 2000.
Scope and Contents
The Stephen G. Bickford papers consist of correspondence, photographs, and newspaper clippings, primarily concerning USAF GLOBE, an organization founded by Bickford to advocate for gay, lesbian, bisexual and transgender non-discrimination for civilians in the Air Force.
Gay military personnel -- United States; Homosexuality; LGBTQ resource; Bickford, Stephen G.
- Inventory, 1980-1999
  - Air Force Gay and Lesbian or Bisexual Employees (GLOBE) files
    - Air Force Federal GLOBE, 1980-1997
      - Ephemera and correspondence, 1997 January-1997 June (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Federal employment memoranda, meeting agendas, newspaper articles, press releases, organizational documents, and correspondence, 1980-1997 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
      - Federal Globe Newsletter, 1996 August-1997 May (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Letters from other federal agencies, 1996 July (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Equal Employment Opportunity
      - Military (general), 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Non military (general), 1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Regarding gays in the military, 1984, 1990-1998 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Vacancy announcements related to AFG work, 1992 -1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Poster on protection, 1990 December (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Workplace Discrimination - correspondence and memoranda, 1993-1998
      - Letter from Office of Personnel Management, 1980 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Complaint chart with Office of Personnel Management letter, 1993 November 23 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Assistant Secretary of Defense for Equal Employment Opportunity disabilities Flexiplace letter, 1994 February 11 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Navy Equal Employment Opportunity policy updated, 1994 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Coast Guard policy regarding sexual orientation, 1994 November 23 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Security policy changes by President Clinton, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Department of Justice Equal Employment Opportunity policy, 1996 July 18 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - "Clinton bans sexual orientation discrimination in security" Detroit News Associated Press, 1995 August 5 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Equal Employment Opportunity Update, 1996 August (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Letter to Air Force Materiel Command/DPCL, 1996 December 19 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - The Washington Blade story regarding GLOBE, 1997 January 31 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Press release from the United States Air Force GLOBE, 1997 February 18 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Letter to Air Force Materiel Command/DPCL, 1997 February 19 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Dayton Daily News story, 1997 March 13 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Headquarters Air Force Materiel Command/PA activity update, 1997 March 13 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Inspector General website, 1997 March 28 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Department of Defense letter on sexual orientation, 1997 April 7 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Letter to Bob Ryan regarding Navy with list of documents, 1997 April 15 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Letter from secretary of Air Force, 1997 June (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Letter from John Glenn, 1997 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Letter to unions, 1997 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Washington Blade Air Force article, 1997 July 11 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Guidelines on religion in the workplace, 1997 August 22 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Letter to John Glenn about Army's policy, 1997 August 25 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Running the Combined Federal Campaign booth at Air Force for Dayton Lesbian and Gay Center, 1997 September (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Department of Defense Personnel System May Change, 1997 September 8 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Meeting notice in Dayton Daily News Business Topics, 1997 September 14 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Secretary of the Air Force policy letter, 1997 October 29 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Air Force policy statement, 1997 October 29 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Secretary of the Air Force letter from the Internet, 1997 October 29 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Email regarding Equal Employment Opportunity policy, 1997 November (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Story on Enda in Federal Times, 1997 November 10 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Air Force Materiel Command/CC policy statement, 1997 November 14 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Air Force Materiel Command/CC policy statement (email), 1997 November 14 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Senator John Glenn's letter regarding Army Equal Employment Opportunity policy, 1997 November (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Email to Air Force Materiel Command/DPCL regarding their omission from policy letter, 1997 November 26 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Email regarding the Air Force Policy Letter Digest, 1997 December 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Washington Blade story, 1997 December 5 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Air Force Globe meeting minutes, 1997 December 18 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Gay People's Chronicle letter concerning sexual orientation policy (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Air Force Materiel Command letter from Rhonda B. Hutchins, 1997 December 22 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Letter from Headquarters Air Force Materiel Command/DPCHE, 1997 December 22 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Dayton Voice regarding Air Force GLOBE, 1997 December 24 - 1998 January 7 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Barney Frank's bill to let gays serve in the military, 1998 January 5 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Mike Peter's cartoon, 1998 January 16 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Air Force GLOBE agenda, 1998 January 22 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Gay People's Chronicle regarding GLOBE, 1998 January 23 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Reply from the Army, 1998 January 26 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Navy letter regarding Timothy McVeigh, 1998 February 6 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - General Babbitt letter, 1998 February 6 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Letter from General Babbitt from Internet, 1998 October (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Barney Frank's press release regarding GLOBE, 1998 February 9 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Dayton Voice interview with Stephen Bickford, 1998 February 12-18 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Gay People's Chronicle, 1998 February 20 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Air Force Times interview with Stephen Bickford, 1998 February 23 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Air Force GLOBE press release, 1998 March 13 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Air Force GLOBE business notice, 1998 March 22 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Washington Blade story, 1998 March 27 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Air Force Equal Employment Opportunity with sexual orientation, 1998 April 3 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Letter to the Army from Air Force GLOBE, 1998 April 10 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Email: F. Whitten Peters statement in Skywrighter, 1998 April 20 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - President Clinton's policy statement Executive Order, 1998 May 28 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - National Gay And Lesbian Task Force press release on President Clinton adding sexual orientation to federal employment Equal Employment Opportunity policy, 1998 May 28 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - Air Force Policy Letter Digest includes sexual orientation on Internet, 1998 May (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Washington Blade story regarding President Clinton's Executive Order to federal employment Equal Employment Opportunity policy, 1998 June 5 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Federal Times: President Clinton adds sexual orientation to Federal Equal Employment Opportunity policy, 1998 June 8 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Letters from Wright-Patterson Air Force Base, 1998 June 11-12 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - Letters not sent to Barney Frank, 1998 August 31 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - Assistant Secretary of Defense letter adding sexual orientation to Department of Defense policy, 1998 August 7 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - Bay Area Reporter story on Air Force GLOBE, 1998 November 5 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - San Francisco Bay Area Reporter, Air Force GLOBE story, 1998 November 6 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Job vacancy announcements on the Internet (Army, Navy, Air Force) without sexual orientation, 1999 January (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Letter to Barney Frank about sexual orientation left out of Army, Air Force and Navy civilian job vacancy announcements, 1999 January 22 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - Letter from Barney Frank regarding sexual orientation not added to job vacancy announcements, 1999 January 27 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - Air Force Materiel Command job vacancy announcements without sexual orientation, 1999 January (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - Fax from Barney Frank's Office with letters from Francis Rush, Jr., Department of Defense, 1999 February (Box 2, Folder 52)
      - Email from Personnel regarding a luncheon for Gay Pride month, 1999 February 4 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      - Equal Employment Opportunity or no - Who you gonna call?, Undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
      - United States Air Force GLOBE basic documentation, Undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Personal files
    - Certificates and awards, 1974-1994 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1997 (Box 2, Folder 57-58)
    - Employment, Circa 1989-1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes photographs of Bickford in an operatic performance and at a party.
    - Miscellaneous publications, 1982-1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Topical files
    - Anti-terrorism, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Dayton Lesbian and Gay Center, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Treehouse, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)